要在二维表面上记录三维场景，需要一些技巧，一些洞察力
To record a three dimensional scene on a two dimensional surface requires some skills, some insight
几何学和数学。如果我们看一下那些图纸
into both geometry and mathematics. And if we look at the sorts of drawings that are
由幼儿或我们古代祖先的洞穴壁画完成，很明显
done by young children or the cave paintings of our ancient ancestors, it's clear that
他们没有必要的洞察力。他们所做的图纸非常简单
they didn't have the required insight. The drawings that they do are very simplistic
他们并没有真正捕捉到第三个维度。
and they don't really capture the third dimension.
事实上，为了达成谅解，人类花了很长时间
In fact, it took humanity quite a long time in order to come up with an understanding
怎么做所以这是一幅我从早期文艺复兴时期就非常喜爱的画作
of how to do this. So this is a painting that I love very much from the early renaissance
时代，它非常清楚地表明，基础几何数学一直很精彩
era and it shows, very clearly, that the underlying geometry mathematics has been beautifully
捕获因为当我们看这幅画时，它毕竟只是二维的，它
captured because when we look at this painting, which is after all only two dimensional, it
作为观众激发我们的灵感，一种非常生动的三维感知。
inspires in us as viewers, a very vivid three dimensional perception.
为了实现这种现实，我们需要了解基础几何。和
In order to achieve this realism, we need to understand the underlying geometry. And
在这个特殊的图纸中，我们可以看到很多几何构造线
in this particular drawing here, we can see a lot of the geometric construction lines
由艺术家设置，以确保最终绘画的几何形状
put in place by the artist, in order to ensure that the geometry of the final painting will
是对的。
be correct.
这在法国被提升为一种非常流行的艺术形式，我们在这里看到的是外观
This was elevated to a very popular art form in France and what we see here is what looks
像一个乡村景观的图像通过建筑物的墙上的石窗看到。
like an image of a rural landscape viewed through a stone window in the wall of a building.
当然这只是一种幻觉。它是墙上的一幅二维画
Of course this is just an illusion. It is a two-dimensional painting on the wall of
一个房子。这是它的现代版本，它的街头艺术版本。这出现了什么
a house. This is a modern version of it, a street art version of it. And what this appears
展示是一个通过建筑物的门户，我们可以看到一些着名的纽约
to show is a portal through a building, beyond which we can see some of the famous New York
桥梁，但它再次只是一个二维幻觉，但这次非常庞大
bridges, but again it is just a two-dimensional illusion, but this time on a very massive
规模。
scale.
现在这些幻想非常非常受欢迎，并且有很多人
Now these kinds of illusions are very, very popular and there are a bunch of people who
做美妙的粉笔街头艺术，
do wonderful chalk street art,
这些幻想得到了非常生动的三个
and these illusions have got a very vivid three
对他们的维度，
dimensionality to them,
创造这些作品必须做大量的工作
an enormous amount of work must go into creating these pieces
艺术的。你不能想象粉笔涉及多少
of art. you can't image how much chalk is involved in
创建这样的图像。
creating an image like this.
但是这里发生的是这些画作都是以这样的方式创作出来的
But what's going on here is these paintings have all been created in such a way that the
在我们眼睛的视网膜上产生的刺激与那种刺激完全相同
stimulus that is generated on the retina of our eyes is exactly the same as the sort of
通过观察真实的三维场景产生的刺激。所以这是
stimulus that would be generated by looking at a real three dimensional scene. So it's
然后，提供给我们眼睛和大脑视网膜的相同刺激就是解释
the same stimulus that's supplied to the retina of our eye and our brain then is interpreting
它以正常的方式解释三维世界。它理解
it in the normal way that it goes about interpreting the three-dimensional world. It understands
关于规模的东西，远处的东西很小而且东西很近
something about scale, that things that are far away are small and things that are close
似乎更大。
appear to be larger.
因此，我们在大脑中建立的所有关于三维的知识
So all of the knowledge that we have built up in our brains about the three-dimensional
我们实际生活在这个世界，被欺骗用三种方式来解释这种感觉
world that we actually live in, is tricked into interpreting this sensation in a three
维度方式。
dimensional way.
因此，即使原始场景是三维的，我们仍然可以在我们的眼睛和眼睛上玩耍
So even if the original scene is three-dimensional we can still play tricks on our eyes and at
乍一看所有这些图片都有点令人惊讶，然后是我们的理性部分
first glance all of these pictures are somewhat surprising and then the rational part of our
大脑开始发挥并说“不，杯子不能那么大。一定是杯子
brain kicks into play and say's "No, the cup can't be that big. It must be that the cup
很近，这个人很远。这不可能是小女孩抱着小人物
is close and the person is far away. It can't be that the little girl is holding tiny people
在她的手中。微小的人不存在。
in her hand. Tiny people do not exist.
所以一定是他们是远离我们的全尺寸人，而且这个女孩离我们很近。“
So it must be that they're full size people far away and that the girl is close to us."
所以最初的反应是令人惊讶的，但是当我们开始推理时，
So the initial reaction is one of surprise but then when we start to reason about it,
我们了解这些场景中发生了什么，我觉得玩这个游戏很有趣
we understand what's going on in these scenes and I thought It's be fun to play this game
同样，这里是我的朋友克里斯在我的手指尖上跳舞，但当然克里斯
as well, so here's my friend Chris dancing on the tip of my finger, but of course Chris
是一个全人类的人，实际上他比我说话。
is a full size human being, in fact he's talker than I am.